[theme music playing]
From now on, I'll be the one
to talk to Ivy.
It's time to find out if that woman
is with us or against us.
[Ivy] Señor Julio has returned
to Poblacion Ardiente.
We have to be more careful.
I'll speed up my search
for my mother, Jepoy.
You wouldn't try
to poison me again, would you?
Anyone who opposes me will be punished.
And you, Emilia, I'll make you suffer.
You'll see just how cruel
your father can be.
Grandpa wants to meet with her tomorrow.
Please tell her to be careful
and not to go with them.
You should give me the money
you promised me.
We should join forces.
With your wealth and my influence.
[Ivy] The election's still far off.
Now's not the time.
[Emilia] Raul, I'm sure Papa
will have you killed.
You better stay at your parents' place
in San Ildefonso.
[Ivy] San Ildefonso.
That's where Raul
could be hiding my mother.
I have a suspicion that Miss Aguas
is hiding something.
I want you to follow her.
[Arnaldo] It's important that
I can trust my staff, Madrigal.
If not, you might end up dead.
[Clarita] You aren't alone in
your fight against your father.
We will bring him down by whatever means!
The Torillo's residence?
Go straight ahead.
You'll find an old lone house there.
Is something wrong, Diego?
Do you remember what I told you
last night?
Don't worry. I won't leave
until she comes back.
[tense music playing]
Diego, what's that?
Miss Carlotta, who's this?
That's Miss Prianka, Miss Ivy's mother.
No, not her. The girl. Who is she?
I don't know.
She's probably one of the kids
who used to visit us.
But Ivy told me that she was always alone.
Well, sometimes we'd get
visitors, of course.
Like the children
of Miss Prianka's friends.
Give me that, Diego.
Ivy doesn't like people
looking through her things.
Here.
Finish your drink before you leave.
Ivy called and said
that she might take a while.
Miss Carlotta, I don't mean to be rude…
but is Ivy Miss Prianka Aguas'
real daughter?
-Of course--
-I found information
on the Internet
that says Prianka Aguas'
daughter is Angel Aguas.
Is she Ivy's sister?
And why don't Prianka and Ivy look alike?
I mean, their features--
Ivy took after her father.
And yes, Ivy had a sister. But she's dead.
Good grief, Diego.
Stop with the questions.
I think it's better if you leave now.
I'm so sorry, Miss Carlotta.
Well then, I'll be off.
All right.
[tense music playing]
Diego's catching on to Ivy.
He can't be.
He just can't.
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Please try again later.
[clicks tongue]
Oh, Ivy…
Moving back here has done
you good, Congressman.
It seems like you're recovering very fast.
The love from my family
and the townspeople does wonders, Doc.
Oh, by the way.
I'd like to ask a favor from you.
Can you tell
the other politicians you know,
well, and your patients too…
that Julio Ardiente is back
in town and he's very much okay?
No problem, Congressman. I'll do that.
-Okay.
-Thank you very much, Doc.
Take your medication.
Remember, health is wealth.
Yes.
Doc.
Oh.
-Grandpa.
-[grunts]
Where did Miss Aguas go?
We weren't able to find her, Grandpa.
So, in other words, she got away.
[tense music playing]
Maybe she knew you were following her?
Oh, well. It doesn't matter.
I'm just wondering where
Miss Aguas could have gone.
Has she gone to Manila…
or maybe to my political rivals
in other provinces?
Maybe she and Raul are in cahoots…
along with Emilia.
They might be planning
something against me.
Or against us.
[Julio exhales]
You know, Arnaldo…
I'm losing faith in that woman.
[tense music playing]
What do you want me to do, Grandpa?
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, ma'am?
I'm sorry, but may I ask you something?
-What is it?
-Do you know
where the Torillo house is?
Yes. It's in the middle of that forest.
Um…
Is it still far from here?
Do you think I can drive there?
I don't think so, ma'am.
You better leave it here.
-Can I?
-Yes.
-Can I park my car here?
-Sure.
Just park it at the back of my house.
Thank you, sir.
-Sure. No problem.
-Thank you.
[pensive music playing]
-Thanks again, sir.
-No problem, ma'am.
[pensive music playing]
[tense music playing]
[groans]
[whimpers]
[sobbing]
Mom, are you here?
[screaming]
[dishes break]
[suspenseful music playing]
Mom?
[groans]
[whimpering]
Mom?!
Mom!
[wailing]
[tense music swelling]
[crying]
Mom!
Mom?
[grunts]
Mom!
[grunting]
Mom?
[instrumental theme music playing]
Mom…
[gasping]
It's you!
Mom!
-Mom. Mom!
-♪ Let her cry ♪
♪ For she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream, for she's a child ♪
♪ Let the rain fall down upon her ♪
-Mom!
-♪ She's a free and gentle ♪
-My mom! It's really you!
-♪ Flower growing wild ♪
♪ And if by chance that
I should hold her ♪
♪ Let me hold her for a time ♪
♪ But if allowed just one possession ♪
[Ivy weeping] Mom…
♪ I would pick her from
The garden to be mine ♪
You're alive!
I thought you were dead, but you're alive!
Mom.
Mom…
[screaming]
Mom?
Mom? [shushes] Mom?
♪ Be careful how you touch her ♪
Mom.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda
continues playing]
Mom, it's me.
It's me, your daughter.
Don't you recognize me, Mom?
Mom, it's me, Lily.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda
continues playing]
Lily?
Mom.
Yes, Mom, it's me.
It's me, Lily.
I am Lily!
I'm Lily, Mom.
Mom, I'm Lily.
It's me, Lily. Please believe me.
It's me, Mom.
Here, look.
[battery dies]
[solemn instrumental playing]
Mom!
Look at me.
It's me.
Mom, I'm Lily.
Mom.
Mom, it's me, Lily.
Lily Cruz.
My name's Lily Cruz.
My father is Dante Cruz.
[stutters] He was a public attorney, Mom.
And you were a teacher.
Uh…
We moved to Poblacion Ardiente
because Dad was assigned there.
But…
But the Ardientes killed him.
And I thought they killed you too.
I thought you were dead.
Mom, it's me, your Lily.
Mom, I'm your daughter.
Your only daughter.
Mom…
[suspenseful music]
[Dante] Attorney Dante Cruz.
This is my daughter, Lily,
and wife, Camia.
We'll have the peaceful life
you've been dreaming of.
[Camia] Dante?! Dante!
[whimpering]
Mom, what's happening?
[screaming]
-Mom!
-[Camia screaming]
Mom, wait!
Mom!
Mom? Mom!
Mom, hold on.
-[Camia grunting]
-Mom?! It's me, Lily!
Mom!
[Lily knocking on door] Mom!
Mom, open the door.
-[Camia wailing]
-Mom, aren't you happy?
Aren't you happy to see me again?
Mom!
Mom?!
[Camia wailing]
Mom.
You're my mother.
It's me, Lily. I'm your daughter.
Please believe me.
I'm your daughter, Lily.
Mom.
[crying]
[screaming]
Mom!
Mom. Mom.
Mom.
Mom, what's going on?
Can't you remember me?
Or anything?
Mom.
[sniffles]
What did they do to you, Mom?
What did they do to you?
What happened to you?
What did they do to you, Mom?
[tense music playing]
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
Let's get out of here.
We have to, Mom. Please come with me.
I'll take you home.
[grunts, clears throat]
[suspenseful music playing]
Love?
Love?!
What happened, Love?! Why?
Hey…
What happened, Love?!
Why are you crying again?
What happened?!
Does anything hurt?! Tell me! What?
Don't cry. I'm here now.
I won't leave you again.
I'm here now, Jasmin.
[tense music playing]
[groans]
What is it?
Listen to me, love.
What's the problem?
What is it? Is there
something you want to tell me?
Go ahead. I'm listening.
Go on.
Tell me.
What is it?
[tense music continues playing]
Come.
Come with me.
You might need something to eat.
You might be hungry. Come on.
[tense music continues playing]
Raul, you bastard.
Ivy, answer the phone.
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Ivy, where are you?
Where are you?
[phone ringing]
-Hello, Jepoy?
-Nanny.
Jepoy, thank goodness you called!
Are you with Ivy?
You mean she hasn't come home yet?
She hasn't. I've been trying to call her,
but I can't reach her.
Oh, Jepoy!
What if something bad happened to Ivy?!
[exhales]
Uh, don't worry. I'll look for her.
Okay. Please do, Jepoy!
And keep me updated, okay?
-Be careful.
-I will.
Madrigal.
[tense music playing]
Where are you going?
To town, Mayor. For a few drinks.
[tense music playing]
I need you to be here early tomorrow.
Don't be late.
Yes, Mayor.
I'll go on ahead.
All right.
[pensive music playing]
I'm sure of it.
That girl is Lily.
I need to know the truth.
If they don't want to tell me,
then I'll look into it myself.
[pensive music continues playing]
[scoffs]
Emilia.
[exhales]
You pathetic woman.
Look at what you did, love.
You destroyed our doorknob
because you wanted to go out.
You know you can't, right?
It's dangerous out there.
Don't worry, I'm not mad.
Just don't do it again, okay?
Come here.
Did you know I prepared dinner for you?
I'm sure you'll love it.
Auntie Belen said this
is your favorite dish.
She says whenever she cooks this for you,
you always end up eating a lot.
And I'm sure you'll eat a lot of this…
because Auntie Belen
didn't make this, I did.
Here.
I cooked this.
I'll join you. Wait right there.
You know, love?
I know you're uncomfortable here
because this place is dark.
So I want to apologize…
if it's dark and hard to move around.
Why is he calling Mom "love"?
He even called her "Jasmin".
We're only using gas lamps
but look at it, love.
It's romantic, like we're on a date.
And, love, I'll fix those stairs.
I have to close it off.
It's too dangerous for you to go upstairs.
You should stay downstairs, okay?
Let's eat.
I'm excited for you to try this because--
[phone ringing]
Hold on.
Hold on, love.
[phone continues ringing]
Hello?
Good thing you answered my call.
What do you need from me, Papa?
[chuckles lightly]
"Papa"?
You still have the nerve to call me Papa…
after what you did?!
Can you please stop
beating around the bush?
What is it?
Tell it to me straight.
What do you want from me?
You're tough now, huh, Raul?
Well then…
Come here.
Come back to the mansion.
And stop hiding
under your mistress' skirt.
[scoffs]
What? Cat got your tongue?
Or maybe you want my men to come get you?
Well, Raul?
Choose. What do you want?
Hey! Leave your pit and face me.
Stop hiding like a cowardly rat.
Face me, you coward!
If you want me to go there,
then fine, I will.
But I'm not a coward
because I'm not afraid of you.
[laughing]
[sighs deeply]
[pensive music playing]
[clears throat]
I'm sorry about that.
That was an important call.
He might take Mom with him.
I can't let that happen.
I need to find a way
to get Mom out of here.
Guess what, Pa.
The people at the office
are very happy that you're back.
I'm glad to hear someone is.
What about you, Emilia? Are you happy?
Of course, Papa. I'm--
-Julio!
-Don't lie to me!
But it's okay.
Tonight, all your lies
will come to an end.
You and your husband's lies will end here.
Do you know Raul is on his way here now?
And Arnaldo will finally know the truth.
What do you mean, Grandpa?
Papa, don't do this.
Don't destroy our family.
I'm not ruining it.
On the contrary,
I am strengthening this family.
Because I want us to live together
without hiding any secrets
from each other.
[scoffs]
You know, Arnaldo?
What you'll learn will surprise you.
And I'm sure it will change
how you see both your Mom and your Dad.
Well, I don't want to wait
for Dad anymore, Grandpa.
I want to know now.
Uh…
[dramatic music]
[thudding]
Love, I'm closing this off.
So you can't go upstairs.
Come.
Love…
I'm sorry, but I really have to leave now.
I want all this to end.
I'm doing this for us, for our peace.
Remember, Jasmin, I love you very much.
You are my life.
Don't worry about where I'm going.
They won't hurt me.
They owe a lot to my father.
And I know plenty of secrets about them.
This will all end tonight.
I promise to come back to you right away.
Okay?
You should get some sleep.
Come on.
[tense music playing]
[keys jingle]
[tense music swelling]
I'll be back first thing tomorrow.
[car unlocks]
Mayor, we'll take the other road.
There's an intersection at the end.
We can catch her there.
Ivy… Where are you?
Have you found your mother?
[groans]
Mom, please stand up.
We'll get out of here, okay?
Come here. We have to leave
before he comes back.
-Hurry, Mom.
-I don't want to.
Raul!
Didn't I tell you not to come here?
Where's that father of yours?
-Raul, wait!
-Hold on.
Raul!
Raul! Stop it!
I just want to talk to your father.
Raul!
Raul.
My, my.
I didn't expect you to come here, Raul.
I thought you'd run with your tail
between your legs and cower
under your women's skirts.
-Let's get this over with, Papa.
-Not so fast!
Back off!
What do you think you're doing?!
What now?
Do it! Come closer!
I won't let you hurt Grandpa again!
I know everything. They told me.
I know what you traitors did!
How could you do that?!
And why did you cover it up?!
My own parents? You ingrates!
Hold on, Arnaldo…
Do you know whom you're
pointing your gun at?!
-I'm your father!
-He's my grandfather!
If you think I'm the devil in the flesh…
then what about your grandfather?
He's worse than the devil himself!
I just want to tell you
that what I did to him
was nothing compared
to what he's done to me!
If there's something
I regret not doing, Arnaldo,
that's not killing him!
I should've killed that
worthless grandfather of yours!
How dare you say that in front of me!
You worthless bastard!
Are you really testing me?!
Why, what'll you do?! Tell me!
Why don't you pull the trigger?!
Do it!
Mom, listen to me.
We have to leave
before that bastard returns.
I'll set you free, Mom.
We'll escape together.
Let's go. Hurry up.
Let's go, Mom.
-No. No!
-Mom. Mom!
I'll stay here.
You're staying here?
Mom, what did that man do to you?
Mom, did he abuse you?
Did he make you drink something
that made you forget who I am?
Mom, do you know what that man did to you?
He once tried to rape you.
Then, his wife ordered Dad,
you, and me to be killed!
All of us, Mom!
He's a bad person! So is his family!
-We should leave.
-No!
-He's kind. He's kind.
-Come on, Mom…
Who's "kind"?!
That man?
You think that bastard is kind?!
He isn't "kind"!
He isn't because he's the reason
why we became like this!
Why we fell apart!
Why our family has become like this!
He isn't kind!
Not even close!
[Jepoy] I couldn't find Ivy…
What if something happened to her?
Let's not jump to conclusions.
Ivy is always ready.
Whatever happens, she can defend herself.
But what if she's already found Camia?
And now Raul has both of them?
I'll see what I can do.
If something that big happens,
the Ardientes will know.
Be careful. Stay away from here for now.
Call or text me any information you have.
-I will.
-Thank you.
Where could she be?
-That's enough!
-What--
Stop it! Stop it, all of you!
That's enough!
Don't do this, Papa.
Please forgive us.
We're sorry, Papa.
I will never forgive you.
You ruined everything.
Especially you, Emilia!
You let ambition and power eat you up.
You've tainted this family's name.
And worst of all,
you killed my good friend.
You killed Pablo!
[grunts]
Enough of that already!
You're hurting Emilia! This isn't right!
I say what's wrong
and right in this house.
And you, don't try to play a hero.
Step aside. Move!
That's enough, Papa! Please…
Stop it, please.
You listen, Emilia!
Everything about you…
everything, is over.
I'll take away your rights
as a mother, a daughter…
and the right to be an Ardiente.
[gasps]
And from that high cloud
you're sitting on,
you will fall.
You are going to resign
as governor of Poblacion Ardiente.
And then people will see you
for who you really are.
A weak, weak woman!
[Emilia crying]
Let's go, Mom.
Believe me, Mom. It's me, Lily!
-Come with me--
-Who is Lily?!
Who is Lily?
Mom, I know you know who Lily is.
Maybe your mind can't remember me,
but I know your heart does.
You didn't tell Raul about me.
Mom, It's me, Lily.
I'm your daughter, Lily.
-I don't have--
-Come on, Mom.
We have to get out of here. Let's go.
-I don't have a daughter.
-Come on, Mom.
-You do. It's me, Lily.
No! I don't!
[sobbing]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[instrumental theme music
continues playing]
You can't do this, Papa.
You cannot do this!
That's unconstitutional! I'll sue you!
I will not give you the right
or the chance to say that!
Because I'll make the people believe
you have a life-threatening disease.
Don't worry, I'll find
the perfect disease for you.
[Emilia crying]
We'll call for
a press conference tomorrow,
so you can announce
your resignation as governor.
No, no, Papa…
Papa, please. I'm begging you.
Please, Papa.
Don't do this to me.
Take away everything from me.
Just let me stay as governor.
Please, Papa. Please.
You want to keep your governorship?
Yes.
That's easy. Here's the solution.
Shoot Raul, and you can continue
being governor.
There's your choice.
Here.
Just kill Raul, and you
can keep your governorship.
[Julio] Well?
[Julio laughs]
So, I see.
You'd rather choose
the life of that imbecile.
Well, that's fine by me.
From now on, none of you
are allowed to leave this house.
We'll show everyone in this town
that we love you
while you battle your sickness.
As for you, Raul,
you'll show everyone that you love Emilia
and you're concerned with her health.
-Is that clear?
-No.
I will leave this house
whenever I want to.
Unless you want me to expose
this family's dirtiest secrets!
-Oh, please. Go ahead.
-Is that so?
Go ahead, Raul. Give me a reason.
Give me one good reason to be rid of you.
And I'm not joking. I will kill you.
Get them out of here!
-Sir, let's go.
-Wait.
-Papa.
-Please come with us, sir.
-Go!
-[Raul] Emilia! Emilia!
-Raul, stop.
-Let go!
-Raul!
-I can't stay here.
[Emilia] Just go with them.
[Raul] Emilia!
[tense music playing]
Carlotta, I know Ivy's
hiding something from me.
And I swear, I'll find out what it is.
What's this interview for?
[Diego] For a magazine feature
on Miss Aguas.
[woman] Ivy?
According to Mrs. Aguas,
Ivy went through a lot.
[Diego] What do you mean, ma'am?
[woman] Something to do with her
childhood and her real mom.
[Camia] Lily! Lily.
Yes, that's me. Do you remember me now?
-Her real mom?
-Yes.
Ivy is Mrs. Aguas' adopted daughter.
-Is this Ivy?
-Yes. That's her.
[Diego] Lily, why did you
have to lie to us?
And why did you come back
to Poblacion Ardiente?
[theme music playing]